Guide to the John Burroughs Papers, 1850-1991 (bulk 1860-1921)
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
- SERIES VI. CORRESPONDENCE: MISCELLANEOUS, 1860-1929
  - To Ursula Burroughs
    - Regarding Invitations, 1904-1919; (2 invitations) (Folder 48.5)
    - West Park Neighbors, (7 letters, 1 postcard, 2 annotated) (Folder 48.6)
  - Ursula Burroughs to Julian Burroughs
    - 1898, (4 letters, 4 annotated) (Folder 48.7)
    - Jan-Feb 1899, (4 letters, 4 annotated) (Folder 48.8)
    - Mar-Apr 1899, (5 letters, 5 annotated) (Folder 48.9)
    - May-Oct 1899, (4 letters, 4 annotated) (Folder 48.10)
    - Nov-Dec 1899, (3 letters, 3 annotated) (Folder 48.11)
    - Jan 1900, (4 letters, 4 annotated) (Folder 48.12)
    - Feb 1900, (4 letters, 4 annotated) (Folder 48.13)
    - Mar-May 1900, (4 letters, 4 annotated) (Folder 48.14)
    - Oct-Dec 1900, (3 letters, 3 annotated) (Folder 48.15)
    - Jan-Feb 1901, (5 letters, 5 annotated) (Folder 48.16)
    - Mar-Apr 1901, (3 letters, 3 annotated) (Folder 48.17)
    - May-June 1901, (4 letters, 4 annotated) (Folder 49.1)
    - Jan-Feb 1914, (2 letters, 2 annotated) (Folder 49.2)
    - Mar-Dec 1914, (3 letters, 3 annotated) (Folder 49.3)
  - Miscellaneous
    - May Cline to Fanny Borden, 1929; (5 letters, 5 cc from Fanny Borden, 1 postcard from Barrus to Borden) (Folder 49.4)
    - Amanda North to Julian Burroughs, 17 July 1912; (original and photocopy) (Folder 49.5)
    - Mary Beal to Julian Burroughs, 1921-1954, undated; (1 letter, 15 postcards, 1 invitation, 5 photocopies) (Folder 49.26)
    - Mary Beal to Clara Barrus, 1909; (1 photocopy) (Folder 49.27)
    - Clara Barrus to Julian Burroughs, 6 Sep 1915; (1 letter, 1 annotated) (Folder 49.17)
    - Charles Lummis to Clara Barrus, 1927; (2 letters, 1 annotated) (Folder 49.18)
    - Pietro to Clara Barrus, Aug 1916; (1 letter) (Folder 49.19)
    - Helen Muir Funk to Mrs. H.A. Haring, 1928; (1 letter, 1 annotated) (Folder 49.20)
    - Charles Lummis to the Harings, 1927; (3 letters) (Folder 49.21)
    - Bliss Carmen to "Aunt" Laura Mackay, 1897-1928, undated; (includes some annotated by Mackay) (Folder 55.1)
    - Unidentified Vassar College student to her parents, circa Feb 1904; (1 fragment) (Folder 49.6)
    - Theodore Roosevelt to George Bird Grinnell (editor Forest and Stream), 24 Apr 1903; (1 carbon, 1 annotated) (Folder 50.4)
    - Unidentified envelope, 4 Sep [no year] (Folder 53.48)
- Series VII. BIOGRAPHY AND FAMILY, 1857-1991
  - Writings about JB
    - "John Burroughs," Scribner's, Jan 1877; (galley proof, missing first page) (Folder 65.1 (Oversize))
    - "John Burroughs: A Day at Riverby and Slabsides, The Craftsman, Aug 1905 (Folder 63.1)
    - Kelley, Elizabeth Burroughs — "JB and Vassar" (Folder 63.2)
    - Kelley, Elizabeth Burroughs — "A Granddaughter of John Burroughs (Folder 63.3)
    - Raymond, Cornelia — "John Burroughs interest in Vassar" (Folder 63.4)
    - Steiger, Neal — "Whitman and Burroughs: Comrades in Criticism,", 1983 (Folder 63.5)
    - Treitel, Phyllis — "Introducing John Burroughs" (includes correspondence from Treitel to EBK) (Folder 63.6)
    - Miscellaneous Articles, 1877-1921 (Folder 63.7)
    - Miscellaneous Articles, 1921 (Folder 65.13 (Oversize))
    - Miscellaneous Articles, 1923-1969 (Folder 63.8)
    - Miscellaneous Articles, 1970-1989, undated (Folder 63.9)
    - John Burroughs Review — Galley, July 1991 (Folder 63.10)
    - Poems about Burroughs, 1882, undated (Folder 63.11)
    - Untitled song by members of the Vassar College Wake Robin Club, Oct 1908 (Folder 63.12)
    - Burroughs, John — "Boyhood of the Late John Burrough's as Described by Naturalist Himself," New York Tribune, 3 April 1921 (Folder 65.16 (Oversize))
  - Honors
    - General — During his lifetime, 1892-1920, undated (Folder 63.13)
    - General — At the time of his death, 1921 (Folder 63.14)
    - General — Since his death, 1931-1988, undated (Folder 63.15)
    - Slide Mountain — Clippings, 1921, 1924, 1964 (Folder 55.10)
    - Slide Mountain — Correspondence, 1921-1924 (Folder 55.11)
    - Slide Mountain — Petition, 1923 (Folder 55.12)
    - Slide Mountain — Miscellaneous (Folder 55.13)
  - Death
    - Obituaries — Alabama, Alaska, Arkansas (Folder 63.16)
    - Obituaries — California (Folder 63.17)
    - Obituaries — Colorado, Connecticut (Folder 63.19)
    - Obituaries — Delaware, District of Columbia (Folder 63.20)
    - Obituaries — Georgia, Idaho (Folder 63.21)
    - Obituaries — Illinois, Indiana, Iowa (Folder 63.22)
    - Obituaries — Kansas, Kentucky (Folder 63.23)
    - Obituaries — Maine, Maryland (Folder 63.24)
    - Obituaries — Massachusetts (other than Boston) (Folder 63.25)
    - Obituaries — Massachusetts — Boston (Folder 63.26)
    - Obituaries — Michigan, Minnesota (Folder 63.27)
    - Obituaries — Mississippi, Missouri, Montana, Nebraska (Folder 63.28)
    - Obituaries — New Hampshire, New Jersey (Folder 63.29)
    - Obituaries — New York (other than NYC) (Folder 63.30)
    - Obituaries — New York — New York City (Folder 63.31)
    - Obituaries — North Carolina, Ohio (Folder 63.32)
    - Obituaries — Oregon (Folder 63.33)
    - Obituaries — Pennsylvania (includes Philadelphia) (Folder 63.34)
    - Obituaries — Rhode Island, South Carolina (Folder 63.35)
    - Obituaries — Tennessee, Texas, Utah, Vermont (Folder 63.36)
    - Obituaries — Virginia, Washington, West Virginia, Wisconsin, Wyoming (Folder 63.37)
    - Obituaries — Canada (Folder 63.18)
    - Obituaries — Miscellaneous (Folder 63.38)
    - Obituaries — Miscellaneous Photocopies (Folder 63.39)
    - Memorial tributes and statements — Edison, Ford and Firestone (Folder 63.65)
    - Memorial tributes and statements — Miscellaneous (Folder 63.66)
    - Funeral Services — News clippings (Folders 63.67-63.71)
    - Burial — Photocopies of photographs (Folder 63.72)
    - Scrapbook of clippings re. JB's death compiled and annotated by Clara Barrus (Folder 64.21)
    - EBK's lists of JB's obituaries and editorials (Folder 55.9)
  - Images and Art
    - Images of Burroughs used with Obituaries (Folder 63.40)
    - Images of Burroughs used with Obituaries (Folder 63.41)
    - Images of Burroughs clipped from newspapers (Folder 63.42)
    - Printed images of Burroughs and his homes (Folder 63.43)
    - Postcards of Burroughs and his homes (Folder 63.44)
    - Postcards of Burroughs and Woodchuck Lodge (Folder 62.125)
    - Portrait by Princess Lwoff-Parlaghy (Folder 63.45)
    - Portrait by Orlando Rouland (Folder 63.46)
    - Sculpture by Paulo (Folder 63.47)
    - Sculpture by Pietro (Folder 63.48)
  - Travel
    - Amherst and Mt. Holyoke (Folder 50.11)
    - Great Britain (Folder 50.12)
    - Harriman Alaska Expedition, 1899 (Folder 50.13)
    - Hawaii (Folder 50.14)
    - Jamaica (Folder 50.15)
    - Lake Mohonk (Folder 50.16)
    - Paris (Folder 50.17)
    - Yama Farms, Napanoch, NY (Folder 50.18)
    - Map: Caledonian Railroad Tourist Guide (Folder 65.14 (Oversize))
    - Map: Kent, England (Folder 65.14 (Oversize))
    - Map: Chester, England (Folder 65.14 (Oversize))
    - Map: England's Lake District (Folder 65.14 (Oversize))
    - Map: European Railways (Folder 65.15 (Oversize))
    - Map: Colorado (Folder 65.15 (Oversize))
    - Map: Geological Survey Map of Kentucky (Folder 65.15 (Oversize))
    - Map: Geological Survey Map of Yellowstone (Mapcase — Drawer 35)
    - Map: Florida (with attached guidebook) (Mapcase — Drawer 35)
    - Map: Hawaii (Mapcase — Drawer 35)
    - Map: London (with attached guidebook) (Mapcase — Drawer 35)
  - Business and Finance
    - Publishers and Editors — Atlantic, 1910-1920 (Folder 51.8)
    - Publishers and Editors — Doubleday, 1909-1916 (Folder 51.9)
    - Publishers and Editors — Ginn and Company, 1893-1917 (Folder 51.10)
    - Publishers and Editors — Harper and Bros., 1892-1915 (Folder 51.11)
    - Publishers and Editors — Houghton Mifflin — Correspondence to JB, 1876-1920 (Folder 51.12)
    - Publishers and Editors — Houghton Mifflin — Correspondence from JB, 1919-1920, undated (Folder 51.13)
    - Publishers and Editors — Houghton Mifflin — Contracts, 1875-1920 (Folder 56.1)
    - Publishers and Editors — Houghton Mifflin — Statements, 1873-1891 (Folder 56.2)
    - Publishers and Editors — Houghton Mifflin — Statements, 1892-1909 (Folder 56.3)
    - Publishers and Editors — McClure's and McClure, Phillips, 1902-1909 (Folder 51.14)
    - Publishers and Editors — The Outlook — Correspondence to JB, 1907-1912 (Folder 51.15)
    - Publishers and Editors — The Outlook — Correspondence from JB to Hamilton W. Mabie, 1894-1897; [4 ALS] (Folder 51.16)
    - Publishers and Editors — Small, Maynard, and Co., 1903-1908 (Folder 52.1)
    - Publishers and Editors — The University Society, 1916 (Folder 52.2)
    - Publishers and Editors — Miscellaneous (Folder 52.3)
    - Publishers and Editors — Miscellaneous EBK material on publishers (Folder 52.4)
    - Property Map of Riverby, undated; (photocopy) (Folder 52.5)
    - Building specifications for the Burroughs' Washington home, 1867 (Folder 56.4)
    - Deeds for the Burroughs' property in Washington, 1870 (Folder 56.5)
    - Bank books and canceled checks, (3 volumes and 10 checks) (Folder 52.6)
    - Miscellaneous financial items (Folder 56.6)
  - Miscellaneous
    - Burroughs Education — Cooperstown (Folder 63.49)
    - Burroughs Family genealogy, by Elizabeth Burroughs Kelley (Folder 63.50)
    - Marriage Certificate of John and Ursula Burroughs, 12 Sep 1857 (Folder 64.8)
    - Parentage of Julian Burroughs (Folder 63.51)
    - Tribute to Mrs. John Burroughs by Dr. Clara Barrus (Folder 63.52)
    - John Burroughs Memorial Association — General (Folder 63.53)
    - John Burroughs Memorial Association — Talks by Julian Burroughs, folder 1 (Folder 63.54)
    - John Burroughs Memorial Association — Talks by Julian Burroughs, folder 2 (Folder 63.55)
    - Advertisements for JB's books (Folder 63.56)
    - Advertisements for "John Burroughs' Nature Notes" (Folder 64.7)
    - JB's copy of the National Currency Act (Folder 63.57)
    - JB's Mount Tom: An All Outdoors Magazine(annotated by JB), Oct 1905 (Folder 63.58)
    - Edmund Gosse Breakfast program (signed by JB and others), 26 Jan 1885 (Folder 63.59)
    - Unidentified record of guests (signed by JB and others), 1914 (Folder 63.81)
    - "John Burroughs Nature Calendar,", 1925 (Folder 62.123)
    - Postcard of the "More Historical Pageant, Roxbury, NY" (Folder 62.124)
    - Articles referring to the wrong Burroughs, 1921 (Folder 63.73)
    - EBK's notes and clippings re: JB's teaching experiences (Folder 63.60)
    - EBK's notes and clippings re: JB's life in Washington (Folder 63.61)
    - EBK's notes on the Burroughs-Barrus Correspondence (Folders 55.6-8)
    - EBK's notes on West Park and Riverby (Folder 62.126)
    - EBK's notes from Effie Quinn's clippings related to Ulster County (Folder 612.127)
    - Partial list by Clara Barrus of JB's manuscripts, 1925 (Folder 56.7)
    - Miscellaneous EBK notes and photocopies (Folder 56.8)
    - Miscellaneous EBK annotations (does not include the items described) (Box 57)
    - Miscellaneous biographical and family material (Folder 63.62)
- SERIES VIII. RESEARCH AND LIBRARY, 1871-1959
  - Material by and about others
    - Addams, Evangeline (Folder 62.99)
    - Beal, Mary (Folder 62.100)
    - Beal, Mary (Folder 56.10)
    - Beals, Jessie Richmond Tarbox (Folder 62.101)
    - Carmen, Bliss — Clippings collected by "Aunt" Laura Mackay (Folder 55.2)
    - Crump, Walter Gray (Folder 62.102)
    - Edison, Thomas Alva — News clippings (Folder 62.103)
    - Edison, Thomas Alva — Pamphlets about (Folder 62.104)
    - Edison, Thomas Alva — "Inspiration to Youth" (Folder 62.105)
    - Edison, Thomas Alva — Photocopies of correspondence held by Rutgers (Folder 62.106)
    - Edison, Thomas Alva — Winter home in Florida (Folder 62.107)
    - Firestone Family (Folder 62.108)
    - Fisher, Clyde (Folder 62.109)
    - Ford, Henry (Folder 62.110)
    - Ford, Henry (Folder 62.111)
    - Fraleigh, Mary — pages copied from her journal (Folder 56.9)
    - Gould Family (Folder 62.112)
    - Hight, George Ainslee — Leather-bound manuscript translation of The Old English Exeter Book of Riddles, translated as a gift by Hight, also contains letter and envelope from Hight (Folder 53.47)
    - Johnson, Clifton (Folder 62.113)
    - Keeler, Charles A. — "To an Alaskan Glacier", (MS) (Folder 53.46)
    - Lummis, Charles (Folder 62.114)
    - Moran, Thomas (Folder 62.115)
    - Nature Fakers — Drawing of Oriole's Nest by Long, (includes JB's annotations) (Folder 55.3)
    - Nature Fakers — Articles by Long and Demming and EBK's notes (Folder 55.3)
    - Muir, John (Folder 62.116)
    - Picket, Anita Truman (Folder 62.117)
    - Rossevelt, Theodore (Folder 62.118)
    - Rossevelt, Theodore — Sagamore Hill (Folder 62.119)
    - Talbot, Frank and Amanda (Folder 62.120)
    - Thoreau, Henry David (Folder 62.121)
    - Whitman, Walt — "Real Summer Openings," NY Tribune, 20 May 1879; (2 photocopies) (Folder 50.19)
    - Whitman, Walt — "The Dead Carlyle," Boston Literary World, 12 Feb 1881 (Folder 50.20)
    - Whitman, Walt — "Memories of President Lincoln," The Bibelot, Aug 1904 (Folder 50.21)
    - Whitman, Walt — "Supplementary Notes" for Leaves of Grass, 1871 (Folder 50.22)
    - Whitman, Walt — Advertisement for Leaves of Grass, 1872? (Folder 50.23)
    - Whitman, Walt — William White's "A Walt Whitman Poster," American Book Collector, 1959 (Folder 50.23)
    - Whitman, Walt — 1976 facsimile of Centennial Post, 31 Dec 1876, with section on Leaves of Grass (Folder 65.12 (Oversize))
    - Whitman, Walt — "Memories of Walt Whitman," by Alma Calder Johnston, sent to CB by Charles Elliot (Folder 50.24)
    - Whitman, Walt — "At the graveside of Walt Whitman," The Conservator, Apr 1892 (Folder 56.13)
    - Whitman, Walt — Horace Traubel's record (Folder 50.25)
    - Whitman, Walt — Miscellaneous biographical material (Folder 50.26)
    - Whitman, Walt — Printed images (Folder 50.27)
    - Whitman, Walt — Sketch (Folder 64.10)
    - Whitman, Walt — Articles and reviews of biographies collected by CB and possibly JB (Folder 64.11)
    - Whitman, Walt — Lists of Whitman materials collected by CB and possibly JB (Folder 50.28)
    - Whitman, Walt — Lists if printed material owned by CB, at least some given by JB (Folder 50.29)
    - Whitman, Walt — Articles about and reviews of biographies — collected by CB and possibly JB (Folder 56.11)
    - Whitman, Walt — Clippings collected by EBK (Folder 56.12)
    - Whitman, Walt — Birthplace (Folder 51.1)
    - Whitman, Walt — Miscellaneous (Folder 51.2)
    - Wiley, Farida (Folder 62.122)
    - EBK's note cards of biographical information on people related to JB's life (Box 61)
    - London Times, 17 Dec 1920 — kept for article on bees? (Folder 63.74)
  - Photocopies of title pages of books from Burroughs' library
    - Adams, Charles Joseph (Folder 52.7)
    - Alexander, F. Matthias (Folder 52.8)
    - Allen, Francis H. (Folder 52.9)
    - Bacheller, Irving (Folder 52.10)
    - Baker, Smith (Folder 52.11)
    - Bates, Katherine Lee (Folder 52.12)
    - Belt, Thomas (Folder 52.13)
    - Benton, Charles (Folder 52.14)
    - Bergson, Henri (Folder 52.15)
    - Bigelow, Poultney (Folder 52.16)
    - Borland, James, B. (Folder 52.17)
    - Brodhead, J. Milliken Napier (Folder 52.18)
    - Burroughs, John (Folder 52.19)
    - Burt, Mary E. (Folder 52.20)
    - Carlyle, Thomas (Folder 52.21)
    - Carpenter, Edward (Folder 52.22)
    - Cawein, Madison (Folder 52.23)
    - Clare, Maurice (Folder 52.24)
    - Denton, William (Folder 52.25)
    - Dimock, A.W. (Folder 52.26)
    - Elizabeth (Folder 52.27)
    - Emerson, Ralph W (Folder 52.28)
    - Frost, Robert (Folder 52.29)
    - Garland, Hamlin (Folder 52.30)
    - Gibson, William Hamilton (Folder 52.31)
    - Gilder, Richard Watson (Folder 52.32)
    - Grahame, James (Folder 52.33)
    - Haldane, Joseph (Folder 52.34)
    - Hale, Edward (Folder 52.35)
    - Harris, Joel C. (Folder 52.36)
    - Henderson, Alice Palmer (Folder 52.37)
    - Holmes, Oliver Wendell (Folder 52.38)
    - Hubbard, Ebert (Folder 52.39)
    - Ibsen, Henrik (Folder 52.40)
    - Ingersoll, Ernest (Folder 52.41)
    - Jenks, Albert Ernest (Folder 52.42)
    - Jesse, Edward (Folder 52.43)
    - Keller, Helen (Folder 52.44)
    - Kennedy, William Sloane (Folder 52.45)
    - Kunz, George Frederick (Folder 52.46)
    - Legallienne, Richard (Folder 53.1)
    - Lloyd, J. William (Folder 53.2)
    - Lord, William Rogers (Folder 53.3)
    - Loveman, Robert (Folder 53.4)
    - Lowell, James R (Folder 53.5)
    - Lubbock, John (Folder 53.6)
    - Lunt, Horace (Folder 53.7)
    - Mabie, Hamilton W (Folder 53.8)
    - McCulloch-Williams, Martha (Folder 53.9)
    - Meany, Edmond S. (Folder 53.10)
    - Miles, Emma B (Folder 53.11)
    - Miller, Mary Rogers (Folder 53.12)
    - Muir, John (Folder 53.13)
    - Nelson, Harry Leverett (Folder 53.14)
    - O'Connor, William (Folder 53.15)
    - Pomeroy, H.S. (Folder 53.16)
    - Porter, Grace Cleveland (Folder 53.17)
    - Rankin, Henry B. (Folder 53.18)
    - Rickert, Edith (Folder 53.19)
    - Riddle, A.G. (Folder 53.20)
    - Riley, James W (Folder 53.21)
    - Roberts, Charles (Folder 53.22)
    - Roosevelt, Theodore R (Folder 53.23)
    - Scott, Walter (Folder 53.24)
    - Scudder, Horace (Folder 53.25)
    - Sinclair, Upton (Folder 53.26)
    - Skinner, Charles M. (Folder 53.27)
    - Sloane, Julia M. (Folder 53.28)
    - Step, Edward (Folder 53.29)
    - Stoddard, John L. (Folder 53.30)
    - Stuart, Ruth McEnery (Folder 53.31)
    - Swinburne, Algernon C (Folder 53.32)
    - Terry, M.O. (Folder 53.33)
    - Thoreau, Henry D (Folder 53.34)
    - Trowbridge, John T (Folder 53.35)
    - Van Dyke, John C. (Folder 53.36)
    - Velvin, Ellen (Folder 53.37)
    - Wade, Blanche Elizabeth (Folder 53.38)
    - Washburn, Charles (Folder 53.39)
    - Wheeler, W. Reginald (Folder 53.40)
    - Whitman, Walt (Folder 53.41)
    - Williams, Marshall Bruce (Folder 53.42)
    - Witchell, C.A. (Folder 53.43)
    - Wood, Frances (Folder 53.44)
    - Miscellaneous (Folder 53.45)
- SERIES IX. PHOTOGRAPHS, 1857-1927
  - Formal Portraits of Burroughs
    - Small framed daguerreotype (with a woven plait of JB's hair), 1857 (Box 60)
    - Copy of early portrait, circa 1860s (Folder 59.99)
    - Outside with his dog "I Know" — Photographer: John Jewell Smith, before 1889 (Folder 58.1)
    - Outside with his dog "I Know" — Photographer: John Jewell Smith, before 1889 (Folder 60.5)
    - Seated at Slabsides — Photographer: M.H. Tannahill, 1900 (Folder 60.6)
    - Seated with book — Photographer: Laura Mackay, 1909 (Folder 58.2)
    - Seated with book — Photographer: Laura Mackay, 1909 (Folder 58.3)
    - Standing by the sea, presumably in California, 1911 (Folder 58.4)
    - Seated — Photographer: Charles F. Lummis, 1921 (Folder 59.98)
    - Standing at the edge of the Grand Canyon — Photographer: "Mr. Moon,", undated (Folder 58.5)
    - Seated — Photographer: possibly J. J. Smith, father of Hilda Smith, undated (Folder 58.6)
    - Seated, undated (Folder 58.7)
    - Seated, undated; (framed) (Box 66 (Oversize))
    - Seated with folded hands, undated (Folder 59.103)
    - Seated — Copy of portrait hung in West Park school house, undated (Folder 58.8)
    - Standing at Slabsides steps — Copy from a postcard in the album of Katharine Brown White (VC 1912), undated (Folder 58.9)
    - Writing at Slabsides desk — Photographer: Clifton Johnson, undated (Folder 58.10)
    - Seated on Slabsides porch, undated (Folder 58.11)
    - Standing on grounds at Riverby, undated (Folder 64.6)
    - Standing on grounds at Riverby, undated (Folder 60.7)
    - Head shot— Photographer: Pirie MacDonald, undated (Folder 60.8)
  - Candids of Burroughs
    - Outside with his dog "I Know" at the Van Benschoten's — Photographer: probably John J. Smith, 1888 or 1889 (Folder 58.12)
    - Seated on a rock, circa 1899 (Folder 58.13)
    - Fishing for trout at Ampusand, 1900 (Folder 58.14)
    - On the water at Upper Ausable, 1902 (Folder 58.15)
    - On a horse at the Gill Ranch, Montana, 1903 (Folder 58.16)
    - Standing above Lake Mohonk, 1904? (Folder 60.3)
    - At the Roxmor Inn, Woodland Valley, NY — Copy from album of Elizabeth H. Haight (VC 1894), Sep 1907 (Folder 58.17)
    - By the water at the Roxmor Inn, Woodland Valley, NY — Copy from album of Elizabeth H. Haight (VC 1894), Sep 1907 (Folder 64.5)
    - In Pasadena, CA, Apr 1909 (Folder 58.18)
    - Receiving honorary degree from Yale University, 1910 (Folder 58.19)
    - At Yale University — Photographer: Annabel Phelps, 1910 (Folder 58.20)
    - At Yale University in procession with faculty and administrators, 1910 (Folder 59.26)
    - Feeding bird indoors in Athens, GA — Photographer: Richard De Loach, 1913 (Folder 58.21)
    - Feeding bird indoors in Athens, GA — Photographer: Richard De Loach, 1913 (Folder 58.22)
    - Standing in front of the Walden cairn — Photographer: Glen Buck, 31 Aug 1913 (Folder 59.63)
    - Seated outside at Sachem Head, CT, 1915? (Folder 58.23)
    - Walking in a field, undated (Folder 58.24)
    - Clamming on Long Island — Photographer: Minnie Rouland (according to EBK's book), undated (Folder 58.25)
    - Leaning on a post at the camp of Laura Mackay and Jeanne Bertrand, undated (Folder 58.26)
    - Writing outside at the camp of Laura Mackay and Jeanne Bertrand, undated (Folder 58.27)
    - Sitting on a rock at the camp of Laura Mackay and Jeanne Bertrand, undated (Folder 58.28)
    - Writing on a rock at the camp of Laura Mackay and Jeanne Bertrand, undated (Folder 58.29)
    - Standing in a field — Copy of image from album of Jeannette H. Ware (VC 1905), undated (Folder 58.30)
    - Bird watching — Photographer: Clifton Johnson, undated (Folder 58.31)
    - Standing in vineyards with a view of the Hudson — possibly at Riverby, undated (Folder 58.32)
    - Examining a rabbit's nest — Photographer: Julian Burroughs, undated (Folder 58.33)
    - Holding a skunk — Photographer: Julian Burroughs, undated (Folder 58.34)
    - At Emerson's grave, Concord, MA, undated (Folder 58.35)
    - Fishing in Frost Valley, NY, near the home of Mrs. Karl Connell, undated (Folder 58.36)
    - Fishing in Frost Valley, NY, near the home of Mrs. Karl Connell, undated (Folder 58.37)
    - Fishing in Frost Valley, NY, near the home of Mrs. Karl Connell, undated; (negative) (Folder 58.38)
    - Talking outside with 2 men, undated (Folder 59.103)
  - Slabsides
    - Cabin exterior, circa 1899 (Folder 58.39)
    - Cabin exterior, undated (Folder 58.40)
    - Cabin exterior, undated (Folder 58.41)
    - Cabin exterior, undated (Folder 58.42)
    - Cabin exterior, undated (Folder 58.43)
    - Cabin exterior, undated (Folder 58.44)
    - Cabin exterior, undated (Folder 58.45)
    - Cabin exterior, undated (Folder 58.46)
    - Cabin exterior — "Slabsides from the spring" — Copy 1, undated (Folder 58.47)
    - Cabin exterior — "Slabsides from the spring" — Copy 2, undated (Folder 58.48)
    - Cabin interior — the hearth, undated (Folder 58.49)
    - JB at writing desk — Copy 1, circa 1900 (Folder 58.50)
    - JB at writing desk — Copy 2, circa 1900 (Folder 58.51)
    - JB at writing desk — Copy 3, circa 1900 (Folder 58.52)
    - JB at writing desk — Copy 4, circa 1900 (Folder 58.53)
    - JB at writing desk, undated (Folder 58.54)
    - JB in dining area — Copy from stereograph by Underwood and Underwood, undated (Folder 58.55)
    - JB sitting in dining area, 1903; [cracked in two pieces — piece 1] (Folder 60.19)
    - JB sitting in dining area, 1903; [cracked in two pieces — piece 2] (Folder 60.20)
    - JB at top of porch steps, undated (Folder 58.56)
    - JB standing on porch steps — Copy from album of Helen Clemence St. Peter (VC 1907), circa 1907 (Folder 58.57)